<!--
MIT License

Copyright (c) 2020 Vikram K. Mulligan, Center for Computational Biology,
Flatiron Institute.

Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy
of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"), to deal
in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights
to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell
copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is
furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:

The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in all
copies or substantial portions of the Software.

THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE
AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM,
OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN THE
SOFTWARE.
-->

<ROSETTASCRIPTS>
        # This script takes as input the 4EXS structure with a 2-residue peptide in the
        # active site and extends it to generate an 8-residue peptide, in an open
        # conformation.  It uses generalized kinematic closure to close the peptide, forming
        # an N-to-C peptide macrocycle.  It then designs the sequence of the peptide, and
        # applies various filters.  If filters pass, it proceeds to carry out a Monte Carlo
        # search of local conformation space, designing at each step, to try to improve the
        # shape complementarity.
        # 
        # This script was updated for the Rosetta version that was current as of 20 May 2020
        # (Git SHA1 cb360c57ed4ba63d45678afba4bf6a39d8dd958d).  Weekly releases after this
        # point, and Rosetta 3.13, will be able to run it.  This version differs from the
        # version used in 2016 to generate the initial designs insofar as the newer, more
        # efficient hydrogen bond counter is used, the cyclization constraints have been
        # replaced with the chainbreak energy term and cutpoint variants, and the updated,
        # simpler, and less error-prone interface for noncanonical design has been used.  For
        # the original version (to exactly reproduce the 2016 protocol with 2016 releases of
        # Rosetta), see section 2.2.2.
 
    # In the SCOREFXNS section, we define scoring functions used for design and energy
    # minimization.
    <SCOREFXNS>
        # A basic scoring function, with an added penalty discouraging sequences that promote
        # formation of aspartimide byproducts during peptide synthesis.  Note that at the time
        # this script was written, the energy function used was a beta version of the energy
        # function called “beta_nov15”.  It has since been renamed “ref2015”, and is the
        # current default energy function in newer versions of Rosetta:
        <ScoreFunction name="r15" weights="ref2015.wts" >
            <Reweight scoretype="aspartimide_penalty" weight="1.0" />
        </ScoreFunction>
 
        # A “soft” variation of the scoring function with more permissive atomic repulsive
        # potentials, useful for design steps.  This scoring function also activates geometric
        # and amino acid composition constraint terms.
        <ScoreFunction name="r15_soft" weights="ref2015_soft.wts">
            <Reweight scoretype="aspartimide_penalty" weight="1.0" />
            <Reweight scoretype="atom_pair_constraint" weight="1.0" />
            <Reweight scoretype="angle_constraint" weight="1.0" />
            <Reweight scoretype="dihedral_constraint" weight="1.0" />
            <Reweight scoretype="aa_composition" weight="1.0" />
        </ScoreFunction>
 
        # A basic scoring function, with an added penalty discouraging sequences that promote
        # formation of aspartimide byproducts during peptide synthesis.  This version also
        # activates geometric constraint terms and upweights the chainbreak term:
        <ScoreFunction name="r15_cst" weights="ref2015_cst.wts" >
            <Reweight scoretype="chainbreak" weight="40.0" />
            <Reweight scoretype="aspartimide_penalty" weight="1.0" />
        </ScoreFunction>
 
        # A variation on the constrained scoring function with the aspartimide penalty term
        # activated and hydrogen bonding, electrostatic, and chainbreak terms upweighted:
        <ScoreFunction name="r15_highhbond_cst" weights="ref2015_cst.wts" >
            <Reweight scoretype="chainbreak" weight="40.0" />
            <Reweight scoretype="aspartimide_penalty" weight="1.0" />
            <Reweight scoretype="hbond_sr_bb" weight="10.0" />
            <Reweight scoretype="hbond_lr_bb" weight="10.0" />
            <Reweight scoretype="hbond_bb_sc" weight="5.0" />
            <Reweight scoretype="hbond_sc" weight="3.0" />
            <Reweight scoretype="fa_elec" weight="2.0" />
        </ScoreFunction>
 
        # A variation on the previous scoring function that has the amino acid composition
        # penalty activated as well:
        <ScoreFunction name="r15_highhbond_aacomp_cst" weights="ref2015_cst.wts" >
            <Reweight scoretype="chainbreak" weight="40.0" />
            <Reweight scoretype="aspartimide_penalty" weight="1.0" />
            <Reweight scoretype="hbond_sr_bb" weight="10.0" />
            <Reweight scoretype="hbond_lr_bb" weight="10.0" />
            <Reweight scoretype="hbond_bb_sc" weight="5.0" />
            <Reweight scoretype="hbond_sc" weight="3.0" />
            <Reweight scoretype="fa_elec" weight="2.0" />
            <Reweight scoretype="aa_composition" weight="1.0" />
        </ScoreFunction>
    </SCOREFXNS>
 
    # The RESIDUE_SELECTORS section establishes residue selectors, which are rules for
    # selecting a subset of a structure for other modules to operate upon.
    <RESIDUE_SELECTORS>
        # These residue selectors select the peptide, the original stub residues, or just the
        # D-cysteine residue in the stub:
        <Index name="select_peptide" resnums="234-241" />
        <Index name="select_stub" resnums="237-238" />
        <Index name="select_stub_dcys" resnums="237" />
 
        # Select the start and end residues of the peptide: 
        <Index name="select_pep_start" resnums="234" />
        <Index name="select_pep_end" resnums="241" />
 
        # This selector inverts the peptide selection, selecting the target protein:
        <Not name="select_target" selector="select_peptide" />
 
        # These selectors select residues based on backbone conformation, selecting residues
        # with negative and positive backbone phi angles, respectively:
        <Phi name="select_neg_phi" select_positive_phi="false" />
        <Not name="select_pos_phi" selector="select_neg_phi" />
 
        # Since the stub residues of the peptide are not designed, this selector selects only
        # the designable subset of positions:
        <Index name="select_design_positions" resnums="234-236,239-241" />
 
        # This selector selects positions within the peptide with positive phi values, which
        # will only be permitted to assume D-amino acid identities:
        <And name="select_D_positions" selectors="select_design_positions,select_pos_phi" />
 
        # This selector selects positions within the peptide with negative phi values, which
        # will only be permitted to assume L-amino acid identities:
        <And name="select_L_positions" selectors="select_design_positions,select_neg_phi" />
 
        # This selector selects positions within the peptide in backbone bin “A”
        # (corresponding to the left-handed alpha helical region of Ramachandran space:
        <Bin name="select_L_alpha" bin_params_file="ABBA.bin_params" bin="A" />
 
        # This selector selects positions within the peptide in backbone bin “X”, a.k.a.
        # “Aprime” (corresponding to the right-handed alpha helical region of Ramachandran
        # space:
        <Bin name="select_D_alpha" bin_params_file="ABBA.bin_params" bin="Aprime" />
 
        # This selector selects positions within the peptide in backbone bin “B”
        # (corresponding to the left-handed beta strand region of Ramachandran space:
        <Bin name="select_L_beta" bin_params_file="ABBA.bin_params" bin="B" />
 
        # This selector selects positions within the peptide in backbone bin “Y”, a.k.a.
        # “Bprime” (corresponding to the right-handed beta strand region of Ramachandran
        # space:
        <Bin name="select_D_beta" bin_params_file="ABBA.bin_params" bin="Bprime" />
 
        # This selector selects positions on the target near the peptide, which will be 
        # allowed to repack during peptide sequence design:
        <Neighborhood name="select_interface" resnums="234-241" distance="8.0" />
 
        # This selector selects positions far from the interface:
        <Not name="select_not_interface" selector="select_interface" />
 
        # This selector selects positions far from the interface which are part of the target,
        # which will be fixed during design:
        <And name="select_target_far_from_interface"
            selectors="select_not_interface,select_target"
        />
        
        # This selector selects buried residues: 
        <Layer name="select_core" select_core="true" select_boundary="false"
            select_surface="false"
        />
 
        # This selector selects buried positions that are also designable:
        <And name="select_hydrophobic_positions"
            selectors="select_design_positions,select_core"
        />
 
        # This selector selects exposed residues:
        <Not name="select_nonhydrophobic_positions" selector="select_hydrophobic_positions" />
 
        # This selector selects exposed positions that are also designable:
        <And name="select_nonhydrophobic_design_positions"
            selectors="select_nonhydrophobic_positions,select_design_positions"
        />
 
        # The following four selectors select every combination of (negative phi or positive
        # phi positions) and (buried or exposed positions).
        <And name="select_L_hydrophobic_positions"
            selectors="select_hydrophobic_positions,select_L_positions" />
        <And name="select_D_hydrophobic_positions"
            selectors="select_hydrophobic_positions,select_D_positions" />
        <And name="select_L_nonhydrophobic_positions"
            selectors="select_nonhydrophobic_design_positions,select_L_positions" />
        <And name="select_D_nonhydrophobic_positions"
            selectors="select_nonhydrophobic_design_positions,select_D_positions" />
    </RESIDUE_SELECTORS>
 
    # The PACKER_PALETTES section defines palettes of amino acid types that will be used for
    # design by default.  Our default palette should include D-amino acids.
    <PACKER_PALETTES>
        # The CustomBaseTypePackerPalette defines the canonical amino acids as types that will
        # be used by default, and allows the user to add additional types.  We will add the D-
        # amino acid mirror images of the canonical amino acids.
        <CustomBaseTypePackerPalette name="design_palette"
            additional_residue_types="DALA,DASP,DGLU,DPHE,DHIS,DILE,DLYS,DLEU,DMET,DASN,DPRO,DGLN,DARG,DSER,DTHR,DVAL,DTRP,DTYR"
        />
    </PACKER_PALETTES>
 
    # The TASKOPERATIONS section defines task operations, which are rules for controlling the
    # Rosetta packer.  The Rosetta packer optimizes side chain rotamers and carries out sequence
    # design, so task operations define design problems.
    <TASKOPERATIONS>
        # Include the input rotamer, even if it is shifted from a rotamer well, in the set of
        # rotamers allowed at a position:
        <IncludeCurrent name="use_input_rotamer" />
 
        # Sample finer levels of discretization of rotamers:
        <ExtraRotamersGeneric name="extrarot" ex1="1" ex2="1" ex3="0" ex4="0"
            extrachi_cutoff="5"
        />
 
        # Prevent repacking of the NDM-1 target protein:
        <OperateOnResidueSubset name="no_repack_target" selector="select_target" >
            <PreventRepackingRLT />
        </OperateOnResidueSubset>
 
        # Prevent design of the NDM-1 target protein:
        <OperateOnResidueSubset name="no_design_target" selector="select_target" >
            <RestrictToRepackingRLT />
        </OperateOnResidueSubset>
 
        # Prevent repacking of the D-cysteine, L-proline stub within the peptide:
        <OperateOnResidueSubset name="no_repack_stub_dcys" selector="select_stub_dcys" >
            <PreventRepackingRLT />
        </OperateOnResidueSubset>
 
        # Prevent design of the D-cysteine, L-proline stub within the peptide:
        <OperateOnResidueSubset name="no_design_stub" selector="select_stub" >
            <RestrictToRepackingRLT />
        </OperateOnResidueSubset>
 
        # Don't design with cysteine or glycine.
        <ProhibitSpecifiedBaseResidueTypes name="no_cys_gly" base_types="CYS,DCYS,GLY"
            selector="select_design_positions"
        />
 
        # Apply restrictions on allowed residues at positive phi positions that are exposed.
        <ProhibitResidueProperties name="D_design" properties="L_AA"
            selector="select_D_nonhydrophobic_positions"
        />
 
        # Apply restrictions on allowed residues at positive phi positions that are buried:
        <RestrictToSpecifiedBaseResidueTypes name="D_hydrophobic_design"
            base_types="DPHE,DILE,DLEU,DMET,DPRO,DVAL,DTRP,DTYR"
            selector="select_D_hydrophobic_positions"
        />
 
        # Apply restrictions on allowed residues at negative phi positions that are exposed:
        <ProhibitResidueProperties name="L_design" properties="D_AA"
            selector="select_L_nonhydrophobic_positions"
        />
 
        # Apply restrictions on allowed residues at negative phi positions that are buried:
        <RestrictToSpecifiedBaseResidueTypes name="L_hydrophobic_design"
            base_types="PHE,ILE,LEU,MET,PRO,VAL,TRP,TYR"
            selector="select_L_hydrophobic_positions"
        />
 
        # Do not allow repacking of NDM-1 residues far from the peptide:
        <OperateOnResidueSubset name="no_repack_target_far_from_interface"
            selector="select_target_far_from_interface"
        >
            <PreventRepackingRLT />
        </OperateOnResidueSubset>
    </TASKOPERATIONS>
 
    # The FILTERS section defines Rosetta filters, which are Rosetta algorithms to analyze a
    # structure, measure properties of that structure, and accept or reject that structure
    # based on the measured properties:
    <FILTERS>
        # These filters measure shape complementarity of the peptide to the target:
        <ShapeComplementarity name="shape1" min_sc="0.63" min_interface="150" jump="3" />
        <ShapeComplementarity name="shape2" min_sc="0.66" min_interface="150" jump="3" />
        <ShapeComplementarity name="shape3" min_sc="0.66" min_interface="150" jump="3" />
 
        # This filter is used in early stages to discard sampled peptide conformations in
        # which molecular geometry clashes egregiously with the target:
        <ScoreType name="low_stringency_clash" scorefxn="r15" score_type="fa_rep"
            threshold="400"
        />
 
        # Rosetta’s pairwise-decomposable scoring function is unable to detect cases in which
        # three or more hydrogen bond donors all donate to the same acceptor.  This filter
        # detects and eliminates this pathology:
        <OversaturatedHbondAcceptorFilter name="oversat" scorefxn="r15"
            max_allowed_oversaturated="0" consider_mainchain_only="false"
        />
 
        # Count internal backbone-backbone hydrogen bonds, excluding hydrogen bonds between
        # adjacent residues, and discard structures with fewer than 3 internal hydrogen bonds.
        # Note that this filter, which is simpler to configure and faster to evaluate, was not
        # available in earlier releases of Rosetta:
        <PeptideInternalHbondsFilter name="total_hbonds" hbond_cutoff="3"
            exclusion_distance="1" residue_selector="select_peptide"
        /> 
        <PeptideInternalHbondsFilter name="total_hbonds_2" hbond_cutoff="3"
            exclusion_distance="1" residue_selector="select_peptide"
        /> 
 
        # This filter measures the energy, biased towards hydrogen bonds and electrostatic
        # terms, following a Monte Carlo move:
        <ScoreType name="mc_score" scorefxn="r15_highhbond_aacomp_cst" 
            score_type="total_score" threshold="999999"
        />
 
        # This filter is used during the Monte Carlo simulation to compute the value passed to
        # the Metropolis evaluator to determine whether moves pass or fail:
        <CombinedValue name="mc_filter" threshold="99999">
            <Add filter_name="mc_score" factor="1.0" />
            <Add filter_name="shape2" factor="-100.0" />
        </CombinedValue>
    </FILTERS>
 
    # The MOVERS section sets up movers, which operate on a structure to alter it in some way.
    # Some sample conformations, others design sequences, others carry out energy
    # minimization, etc.
    <MOVERS>
        # The PeptideStubMover appends or prepends residues to an existing structure.
        <PeptideStubMover name="extend" >
            <Prepend anchor_rsd="234" resname="GLY" />
            <Prepend anchor_rsd="234" resname="GLY" />
            <Prepend anchor_rsd="234" resname="GLY" />
            <Append anchor_rsd="238" resname="GLY" />
            <Append anchor_rsd="239" resname="GLY" />
            <Append anchor_rsd="240" resname="GLY" />
        </PeptideStubMover>
 
        # The AtomTree mover sets up the fold tree, which defines the kinematic relationships
        # between different parts of a structure:
        <AtomTree name="foldtree1" fold_tree_file="inputs/foldtree1.txt" />
 
        # This SetTorsion mover is used to initialize the torsions for the dihedral angles at
        # the start and end of the D-cysteine-L-proline stub.  It sets these to ideal values
        # and then adds a small random perturbation.  It also ensures that all omega angles
        # are 180 degrees.
        <SetTorsion name="initialize_tors">
            <Torsion residue="234" torsion_name="omega" angle="180.0" />
            <Torsion residue="235" torsion_name="omega" angle="180.0" />
            <Torsion residue="236" torsion_name="omega" angle="180.0" />
            <Torsion residue="237" torsion_name="phi"   angle="60.0" />
            <Torsion residue="237" torsion_name="phi"   angle="perturb"
                perturbation_type="gaussian" perturbation_magnitude="30.0"
            />
            <Torsion residue="237" torsion_name="psi"   angle="perturb" 
                perturbation_type="gaussian" perturbation_magnitude="5.0"
            />
            <Torsion residue="237" torsion_name="omega" angle="perturb"
                perturbation_type="gaussian" perturbation_magnitude="5.0"
            />
            <Torsion residue="238" torsion_name="phi"   angle="perturb"
                perturbation_type="gaussian" perturbation_magnitude="5.0"
            />
            <Torsion residue="238" torsion_name="psi"   angle="-10.0" />
            <Torsion residue="238" torsion_name="psi"   angle="perturb"
                perturbation_type="gaussian" perturbation_magnitude="30.0"
            />
            <Torsion residue="238" torsion_name="omega" angle="180.0" />
            <Torsion residue="239" torsion_name="omega" angle="180.0" />
            <Torsion residue="240" torsion_name="omega" angle="180.0" />
        </SetTorsion>
 
        # This SetTorsion mover adds a smaller random perturbation to all backbone degrees of
        # freedom of the stub:
        <SetTorsion name="perturb_tors">
            <Torsion residue="237" torsion_name="phi"   angle="perturb"
                perturbation_type="gaussian" perturbation_magnitude="5.0"
            />
            <Torsion residue="237" torsion_name="psi"   angle="perturb"
                perturbation_type="gaussian" perturbation_magnitude="1.0"
            />
            <Torsion residue="237" torsion_name="omega" angle="perturb" 
                perturbation_type="gaussian" perturbation_magnitude="1.0"
            />
            <Torsion residue="238" torsion_name="phi"   angle="perturb"
                perturbation_type="gaussian" perturbation_magnitude="1.0"
            />
            <Torsion residue="238" torsion_name="psi"   angle="perturb" 
                perturbation_type="gaussian" perturbation_magnitude="5.0"
            />
            <Torsion residue="238" torsion_name="omega" angle="perturb"
                perturbation_type="gaussian" perturbation_magnitude="1.0"
            />
        </SetTorsion>
 
        # This mover adds a chemical bond between the first and last residues of the peptide.
        # It has the side-effect of correcting the placement of oxygen and hydrogen atoms
        # flanking the amide bond, and so is used repeatedly to update these placements.
        # Note that this is less likely in more recent versions of Rosetta, since the
        # cutpoint variant types have been updated to ensure that hydrogen and oxygen
        # placement remains reasonable at cutpoints during minimization:
        <DeclareBond name="connect_termini" atom1="N" res1="234" atom2="C" res2="241" 
            add_termini="true"
        />
 
        # Add cutpoint variants to the cyclization point in the peptide.  The cutpoint variant
        # works with the chainbreak scoring term to ensure that good amide bond geometry is
        # maintained during energy minimization:
        <ModifyVariantType name="add_cutpoint_upper_pep" add_type="CUTPOINT_UPPER"
            residue_selector="select_pep_start"
        />
        <ModifyVariantType name="add_cutpoint_lower_pep" add_type="CUTPOINT_LOWER"
            residue_selector="select_pep_end"
        /> 
 
        # These movers add amino acid composition constraints to the whole peptide, to
        # negative-phi positions in the alpha-helix region of Ramachandran space, to
        # negative-phi positions in the beta-sheet region of Ramachandran space, to
        # positive-phi positions in the right-handed alpha-helix region of Ramachandran
        # space, and to positive-phi positions in the right-handed beta-sheet region of
        # Ramachandran space, respectively:
        <AddCompositionConstraintMover name="global_comp"
            filename="comp/global_preferences.comp" selector="select_design_positions" />
        <AddCompositionConstraintMover name="L_alpha_comp"
            filename="comp/L_alpha_preferences.comp" selector="select_L_alpha" />
        <AddCompositionConstraintMover name="D_alpha_comp"
            filename="comp/D_alpha_preferences.comp" selector="select_D_alpha" />
        <AddCompositionConstraintMover name="L_beta_comp"
            filename="comp/L_beta_preferences.comp" selector="select_L_beta" />
        <AddCompositionConstraintMover name="D_beta_comp"
            filename="comp/D_beta_preferences.comp" selector="select_D_beta" />
 
        # The PackRotamersMover optimizes side chain rotamers, permitting structure
        # refinement or design.  Here, it is used to design the peptide and to refine
        # side chain conformations on the target.
        <PackRotamersMover name="softdesign" scorefxn="r15_soft"
            packer_palette="design_palette"
            task_operations="use_input_rotamer,no_design_target,no_repack_target,no_design_stub,no_repack_stub_dcys,no_cys_gly,D_design,L_design,D_hydrophobic_design,L_hydrophobic_design"
        />
 
        # The MinMover relaxes a structure through gradient-descent minimization.  This one
        # is configured to minimize only side chains of the peptide.  Note that more recent
        # versions of Rosetta permit more robust configuration of the minimizer through
        # move map factories:
        <MinMover name="min1" scorefxn="r15_cst" type="dfpmin" tolerance="0.001" bb="0"
            chi="0"
        >
            <MoveMap name="min1_mm" >
                <Jump number="1" setting="0" />
                <Jump number="2" setting="0" />
                <Jump number="3" setting="0" />
                <Jump number="4" setting="0" />
                <Jump number="5" setting="0" />
                <Jump number="6" setting="0" />
                <Jump number="7" setting="0" />
                <Jump number="8" setting="0" />
                <Jump number="9" setting="0" />
                <Span begin="1" end="999" chi="0" bb="0" />
                <Span begin="234" end="241" chi="1" bb="0" />
            </MoveMap>
        </MinMover>
 
        # This MinMover permits both side hain and backbone minimization of the peptide, but
        # keeps the rest of the structure rigid:
        <MinMover name="min2" scorefxn="r15_cst" type="dfpmin" tolerance="0.001" bb="0" 
            chi="0"
        >
            <MoveMap name="min2_mm" >
                <Jump number="1" setting="0" />
                <Jump number="2" setting="0" />
                <Jump number="3" setting="0" />
                <Jump number="4" setting="0" />
                <Jump number="5" setting="0" />
                <Jump number="6" setting="0" />
                <Jump number="7" setting="0" />
                <Jump number="8" setting="0" />
                <Jump number="9" setting="0" />
                <Span begin="1" end="999" chi="0" bb="0" />
                <Span begin="234" end="241" chi="1" bb="1" />
            </MoveMap>
        </MinMover>
 
        # FastDesign performs alternating rounds of packing and minimization while ramping the
        # repulsive term in the scoring function from an initial low value.  This FastDesign
        # instance is configured to design the peptide and repack the target interface, and to
        # allow peptide side chains and backbone and target side chains to move during energy
        # minimization.
        <FastDesign name="fdes" repeats="3" scorefxn="r15_highhbond_aacomp_cst" 
            min_type="dfpmin" packer_palette="design_palette"
            task_operations="use_input_rotamer,no_repack_target_far_from_interface,no_design_target,no_design_stub,no_repack_stub_dcys,no_cys_gly,D_design,L_design,L_hydrophobic_design,D_hydrophobic_design"
        >
            <MoveMap name="fdes_mm" >
                <Jump number="1" setting="0" />
                <Jump number="2" setting="0" />
                <Jump number="3" setting="0" />
                <Jump number="4" setting="0" />
                <Jump number="5" setting="0" />
                <Jump number="6" setting="0" />
                <Jump number="7" setting="0" />
                <Jump number="8" setting="0" />
                <Jump number="9" setting="0" />
                <Span begin="1" end="999" chi="1" bb="0" />
                <Span begin="234" end="241" chi="1" bb="1" />
            </MoveMap>
        </FastDesign>
 
        # A ParsedProtocol encapsulates many previously-defined movers and/or filters into a
        # single mover.  This instance defines a series of steps carried out for every
        # solution found by the initial generalized kinematic closure attempts to close the
        # peptide. These steps include filtering based on total hydrogen bonds, presence of
        # oversaturated acceptors, and clashes, design and minimization, additional filtering,
        # and a more expensive FastDesign round if minimal shape complementarity requirements
        # are met after the low-cost steps carried out thus far.  The pattern is to go from
        # inexpensive to expensive computations, deciding whether to discard the attempt or to
        # continue after each step:
        <ParsedProtocol name="genkic_steps">
            <Add filter="oversat" />
            <Add filter="total_hbonds" />
            <Add filter="low_stringency_clash" />
            <Add mover="softdesign" />
            <Add mover="min1" />
            <Add mover="connect_termini" />
            <Add filter="oversat" />
            <Add mover="min2" />
            <Add mover="connect_termini" />
            <Add filter="oversat" />
            <Add filter="total_hbonds_2" />
            <Add filter="shape1" />
            <Add mover="fdes" />
            <Add mover="connect_termini" />
            <Add filter="oversat" />
            <Add filter="shape2" />
        </ParsedProtocol>
 
        # Generalized kinematic closure (GeneralizedKIC) allows efficient sampling of the
        # closed conformations of a chain of atoms, with rapid solution of a series of
        # equations to determine values of certain degrees of freedom in order to keep the 
        # chain closed. This instance is configured to perform the initial closure of the
        # peptide macrocycle. For each closed conformation sampled, the steps listed in the
        # previous ParsedProtocol mover are carried out, and the conformation iis accepted
        # if and only if all steps pass:
        <GeneralizedKIC name="genkic" closure_attempts="100"
            pre_selection_mover="genkic_steps"
            stop_when_n_solutions_found="1" selector="lowest_energy_selector"
            selector_scorefunction="r15_highhbond_cst"
        >
            <AddResidue res_index="239" />
            <AddResidue res_index="240" />
            <AddResidue res_index="241" />
            <AddResidue res_index="234" />
            <AddResidue res_index="235" />
            <AddResidue res_index="236" />
            <SetPivots res1="239" res2="234" res3="236" atom1="CA" atom2="CA" atom3="CA" />
            <CloseBond atom1="C" res1="241" atom2="N" res2="234" torsion="180"
                bondlength="1.328685" angle1="116.2" angle2="121.7"
            />
            <AddPerturber effect="randomize_alpha_backbone_by_rama" >
                <AddResidue index="234" />
                <AddResidue index="235" />
                <AddResidue index="236" />
                <AddResidue index="239" />
                <AddResidue index="240" />
                <AddResidue index="241" />
            </AddPerturber>
        </GeneralizedKIC>
 
        # A second GeneralizedKIC mover is used to perturb the closed peptide macrocycle
        # during the Monte Carlo search.  For each perturbation, these steps (checking for
        # oversaturated hbond acceptors, counting total hbonds) are carried out: 
        <ParsedProtocol name="genkic_perturb_steps">
            <Add mover="connect_termini" />
            <Add filter="oversat" />
            <Add filter="total_hbonds_2" />
        </ParsedProtocol>
 
        # This is the second GeneralizedKIC mover.  This one is configured to add a small,
        # random perturbation to an already-closed peptide macrocycle, ensuring that the
        # macrocycle remains closed after the perturbation.  It is used in the context of a
        # Monte Carlo search of local conformations:
        <GeneralizedKIC name="genkic_perturb" closure_attempts="5"
            pre_selection_mover="genkic_perturb_steps" stop_when_n_solutions_found="1"
            selector="lowest_rmsd_selector" selector_scorefunction="r15_highhbond_cst"
        >
            <AddResidue res_index="239" />
            <AddResidue res_index="240" />
            <AddResidue res_index="241" />
            <AddResidue res_index="234" />
            <AddResidue res_index="235" />
            <AddResidue res_index="236" />
            <SetPivots res1="239" res2="234" res3="236" atom1="CA" atom2="CA" atom3="CA" />
            <CloseBond atom1="C" res1="241" atom2="N" res2="234" torsion="180"
                bondlength="1.328685" angle1="116.2" angle2="121.7" />
            <AddPerturber effect="perturb_dihedral" >
                <AddAtoms res1="239" atom1="N"  res2="239" atom2="CA" />
                <AddAtoms res1="239" atom1="CA" res2="239" atom2="C"  />
                <AddAtoms res1="240" atom1="N"  res2="240" atom2="CA" />
                <AddAtoms res1="240" atom1="CA" res2="240" atom2="C"  />
                <AddAtoms res1="241" atom1="N"  res2="241" atom2="CA" />
                <AddAtoms res1="241" atom1="CA" res2="241" atom2="C"  />
                <AddAtoms res1="234" atom1="N"  res2="234" atom2="CA" />
                <AddAtoms res1="234" atom1="CA" res2="234" atom2="C"  />
                <AddAtoms res1="235" atom1="N"  res2="235" atom2="CA" />
                <AddAtoms res1="235" atom1="CA" res2="235" atom2="C"  />
                <AddAtoms res1="236" atom1="N"  res2="236" atom2="CA" />
                <AddAtoms res1="236" atom1="CA" res2="236" atom2="C"  />
                <AddValue value="2.5" />
            </AddPerturber>
        </GeneralizedKIC>
 
        # These movers are used only for debugging, not in production runs:
        <PDBTrajectoryRecorder name="record_traj" stride="1" filename="traj.pdb"
            cumulate_jobs="0" cumulate_replicas="0" />
        <PDBTrajectoryRecorder name="record_traj_accepted" stride="1" filename="accepted.pdb"
            cumulate_jobs="0" cumulate_replicas="0" />
 
        # This is the series of steps performed as the move in the Monte Carlo search.  First,
        # the stub and the macrocycle are perturbed slightly.  Next, a quick round of design
        # is carried out, followed by side chain minimization.  Then, filters are applied.
        # Then, the backbone is minimized, followed by more filtering.  If all of this
        # passes, the move is accepted or rejected by the Metropolis criterion:
        <ParsedProtocol name="mc_steps">
            Add mover=record_traj_accepted /> #COMMENTED OUT FOR PRODUCTION RUNS.
            <Add mover="perturb_tors" />
            <Add mover="genkic_perturb" />
            <Add mover="softdesign" />
            <Add mover="min1" />
            <Add mover="connect_termini" />
            Add mover=record_traj /> #COMMENTED OUT FOR PRODUCTION RUNS.
            <Add filter="oversat" />
            <Add mover="min2" />
            <Add mover="connect_termini" />
            <Add filter="oversat" />
            <Add filter="total_hbonds_2" />
        </ParsedProtocol>
 
        # This mover actually carries out the Monte Carlo search of local conformation space,
        # executing the series of steps in the previous ParsedProtocol as the moves in the
        # search:
        <GenericMonteCarlo name="mc_search" mover_name="mc_steps" filter_name="mc_filter"
            trials="500" temperature="0.5"
        />
 
        # FsstRelax performs alternating rounds of side chain packing and minimization,
        # keeping sequence fixed but ramping repulsive terms in the scoring function.  It
        # is used for final structural refinement:   
        <FastRelax name="final_frlx" repeats="3" scorefxn="r15_cst" min_type="dfpmin"
            task_operations="use_input_rotamer,no_repack_target_far_from_interface"
        >
            <MoveMap name="final_frlx_mm" >
                <Jump number="1" setting="0" />
                <Jump number="2" setting="0" />
                <Jump number="3" setting="0" />
                <Jump number="4" setting="0" />
                <Jump number="5" setting="0" />
                <Jump number="6" setting="0" />
                <Jump number="7" setting="0" />
                <Jump number="8" setting="0" />
                <Jump number="9" setting="0" />
                <Span begin="1" end="999" chi="1" bb="0" />
                <Span begin="234" end="241" chi="1" bb="1" />
            </MoveMap>
        </FastRelax>
    </MOVERS>
 
    # The PROTOCOLS section strings together previously-defined movers and filters to
    # construct an overall protocol.  Our overall protocol is to initialize the structure
    # and add cutpoint variant types, perform an initial closure of the macrocycle in which
    # an initial sequence is designed, then carry out a Monte Carlo search of the local
    # conformational space, redesigning the macrocycle sequence at each step.  Final
    # relaxation and filtering to measure shape complementarity complete the protocol.
    <PROTOCOLS>
        <Add mover="extend" />
        <Add mover="foldtree1" />
        <Add mover="initialize_tors" />
        <Add mover="connect_termini" />
        <Add mover="add_cutpoint_upper_pep" />
        <Add mover="add_cutpoint_lower_pep" />
        <Add mover="global_comp" />
        <Add mover="L_alpha_comp" />
        <Add mover="D_alpha_comp" />
        <Add mover="L_beta_comp" />
        <Add mover="D_beta_comp" />
        <Add mover="genkic" />
        <Add mover="mc_search" />
        <Add mover="fdes" />
        <Add mover="final_frlx" />
        <Add mover="connect_termini" />
        <Add filter="oversat" />
        <Add filter="shape3" />
    </PROTOCOLS>
 
    # The OUTPUT section defines the scoring function that will be used to produce the final
    # score for the structure.
    <OUTPUT scorefxn="r15" />
</ROSETTASCRIPTS>
