<ROSETTASCRIPTS>
        # Given an input structure of a candidate inhibitor peptide bound to NDM-1, this
        # script estimates the delta-G of binding using the (poorly-named) ddG protocol.
        # It carries out relaxation of both bound and unbound structures, allowing small
        # motions of the hinge loop.
        #
        # This script was tested with the current version of Rosetta (Git SHA1
        # cb360c57ed4ba63d45678afba4bf6a39d8dd958d). It should be compatible with all Rosetta 
        # versions after weekly release 2020.11.
 
    # Scoring functions are defined in this section:
    <SCOREFXNS>
        # The default Rosetta energy function, ref2015, with the metalbinding constraint
        # turned OFF explicitly.  We will use this for scoring the bound and unbound states, 
        # to ensure that the metal coordination is not artificially inflating the score.
        <ScoreFunction name="r15" weights="ref2015" >
            <Reweight scoretype="metalbinding_constraint" weight="0.0" />
        </ScoreFunction>
        # The default energy function with the chainbreak term upweighted:
        <ScoreFunction name="r15_cst" weights="ref2015_cst" >
            <Reweight scoretype="metalbinding_constraint" weight="1.0" />
            <Reweight scoretype="chainbreak" weight="20.0" />
        </ScoreFunction>
        # The default energy function with the chainbreak term upweighted and the metalbinding
        # constraint term explicitly turned OFF.  See note above.
        <ScoreFunction name="r15_cst_nometal" weights="ref2015_cst" >
            <Reweight scoretype="metalbinding_constraint" weight="0.0" />
            <Reweight scoretype="chainbreak" weight="20.0" />
        </ScoreFunction>
    </SCOREFXNS>
 
    # Residue selectors, used to configure modules that operate on a subset of a pose, are
    # declared here:
    <RESIDUE_SELECTORS>
        # Select the peptide:
        <Index name="select_pep" resnums="234-241" />
 
        # Select the flexible hinge loop:
        <Index name="select_hinge_loop" resnums="25-33" />
 
        # Select the vicinity of the peptide (including the peptide):
        <Neighborhood name="select_near_pep" selector="select_pep" distance="10.0"
            include_focus_in_subset="true" />
 
        # Select residues that are not in the vicinity of the peptide.  This selection 
        # excludes the peptide:
        <Not name="select_not_near_pep" selector="select_near_pep" />
 
        # Select a previously-stored selection of residues representing the interface between
        # peptide and target.
        <StoredResidueSubset name="selected_near_pep" subset_name="interface" />
 
        # Select those residues that are not in the stored selection above.
        <Not name="selected_not_near_pep" selector="selected_near_pep" />
 
        # Select the upper residue in the cutpoints in the peptide macrocycle and in the
        # hinge loop (to apply the cutpoint upper variant type):
        <Index name="select_upper_cutpoints" resnums="30,234" />
 
        # Select the lower residue in the cutpoints in the peptide macrocycle and in the
        # hinge loop (to apply the cutpoint lower variant type):
        <Index name="select_lower_cutpoints" resnums="29,241" />
    </RESIDUE_SELECTORS>
 
    # Task operations, which control the Rosetta packer during rotamer optimization, are 
    # defined here.  Note that we do no design in this script, but still use the packer to 
    # optimize rotamer conformation:
    <TASKOPERATIONS>
        # Prevent design everywhere:
        <RestrictToRepacking name="repack_only" />
 
        # Prevent repacking far from the peptide:
        <OperateOnResidueSubset name="only_near_pep" selector="selected_not_near_pep" >
            <PreventRepackingRLT />
        </OperateOnResidueSubset>
 
        # Ensure that the input rotamer is included in the set of rotamers considered during
        # rotamer optimization:
        <IncludeCurrent name="include_current" />
 
        # Enable finer discretization of rotamers:
        <ExtraRotamersGeneric name="ex1_ex2" ex1="true" ex2="true" extrachi_cutoff="0" />
    </TASKOPERATIONS>
 
    # Jump selectors select rigid-body transforms when configuring move map factories, which
    # control energy minimization steps:
    <JUMP_SELECTORS>
        # Select the rigid-body degree of freedom connecting the target to the peptide:
        <JumpIndex name="select_pep_jump" jump="4" />
    </JUMP_SELECTORS>
 
    # Move map factories control energy minimization steps by defining which degrees of
    # freedom are movable and which are fixed:
    <MOVE_MAP_FACTORIES>
        # The move map factory for the relaxation that is carried out on the bound complex.
        # Here, we allow only the side chains near the peptide, only the backbone of the
        # peptide and the hinge loop, and only the rigid-body transform from NDM-1 to peptide
        # to move during energy minimization:
        <MoveMapFactory name="mmf_prerelax" bb="false" chi="false" jumps="0" >
            <Chi enable="true" residue_selector="selected_near_pep" />
            <Jumps enable="true" jump_selector="select_pep_jump" />
            <Backbone enable="true" residue_selector="select_hinge_loop" />
            <Backbone enable="true" residue_selector="select_pep" />
        </MoveMapFactory>
 
        # The move map factory for the relaxation that is carried out on the separated
        # peptide and target.  Here, we allow only the side chains that had been at the
        # interface, and only the backbone of the peptide and the hinge loop to move.  All
        # rigid-body degrees of freedom are fixed during this relaxation:
        <MoveMapFactory name="mmf_post_separation" bb="false" chi="false" jumps="0" >
            <Chi enable="true" residue_selector="selected_near_pep" />
            <Backbone enable="true" residue_selector="select_hinge_loop" />
            <Backbone enable="true" residue_selector="select_pep" />
        </MoveMapFactory>
    </MOVE_MAP_FACTORIES>
 
    # Movers alter a structure in some way.  Here we define a mover that will be used by
    # the Ddg filter, which repacks and energy-minimizes the separated peptide and target:
    <MOVERS>
        <FastDesign name="frlx_for_filter" repeats="3" scorefxn="r15_cst_nometal"
            task_operations="repack_only,only_near_pep,include_current,ex1_ex2"
            movemap_factory="mmf_post_separation"
        />
    </MOVERS>
 
    # Filters are used to measure properties of a structure and to make pass/fail decisions.
    # Here, we define the Ddg filter that will be used to measure the energy of the bound and
    # separated structures, and to report the difference.  This filter takes as input a
    # FastRelax mover, defined above, which is applied to the separated complex.
    <FILTERS>
        <Ddg name="ddg" jump="4" confidence="0" threshold="0.0" scorefxn="r15" repeats="15"
            repack="true" repack_unbound="false" relax_unbound="true" repack_bound="false"
            relax_bound="false" relax_mover="frlx_for_filter" translate_by="10000"
            extreme_value_removal="true"
        />
    </FILTERS>
 
    # Here we define additional movers:
    <MOVERS>
        # Connect the ends of the peptide to make an N-to-C cyclic macrocycle:
        <DeclareBond name="endbond" res1="234" res2="241" atom1="N" atom2="C" />
 
        # Set up the kinematic directed acyclic graph (DAG) for the structure:
        <AtomTree name="foldtree" fold_tree_file="inputs/foldtree.txt" />
 
        # Add cutpoint variant types to the residues flanking the cutpoints in the macrocycle
        # and in the hinge loop:
        <ModifyVariantType name="add_upper_cutpoints" add_type="CUTPOINT_UPPER"
            residue_selector="select_upper_cutpoints" />
        <ModifyVariantType name="add_lower_cutpoints" add_type="CUTPOINT_LOWER"
            residue_selector="select_lower_cutpoints"/>
 
        # Identify interface residues and store this residue selection in the pose for later
        # retrieval after the complex is separated:
        <StoreResidueSubset name="store_interface" residue_selector="select_near_pep"
            subset_name="interface" />
 
        # FastDesign with the RestrictToRepacking task operation does the same thing that
        # FastRelax would.  It is used here for convenience for the step of relaxing the
        # bound complex, since it reports the residues that it is repacking (while FastRelax
        # is less verbose):
        <FastDesign name="frlx" repeats="3" scorefxn="r15_cst"
            task_operations="repack_only,only_near_pep,include_current,ex1_ex2"
            movemap_factory="mmf_prerelax"
        />
 
        # Remove constraints from the pose:
        <ClearConstraintsMover name="clear_csts" />
    </MOVERS>
 
    # This section puts together previously-defined movers and filters to construct an
    # overall protocol:
    <PROTOCOLS>
        <Add mover="endbond" />
        <Add mover="foldtree" />
        <Add mover="add_upper_cutpoints" />
        <Add mover="add_lower_cutpoints" />
        <Add mover="store_interface" />
        <Add mover="frlx" />
        <Add mover="clear_csts" />
        <Add filter="ddg" report_at_end="false" />
    </PROTOCOLS>
 
    # At the end, the ref2015 energy function is used to score the output pose: 
    <OUTPUT scorefxn="r15" />
</ROSETTASCRIPTS>
