<ROSETTASCRIPTS>
        # This script takes as input PDB structure 4EXS in which the L-captopril has been
        # converted to a D-cysteine, L-proline dipeptide stub.  It then extends this stub,
        # prepending three glycine residues and appending three glycine residues.  Finally, it
        # sets the omega torsion angles of all of these residues to 180 degrees.
        # 
        # This script was tested against Rosetta weekly release 2016.46 (Git SHA1
        # 47669d9d2e9f659f4889dc89ee6305575dd87c2e).  It is NOT RECOMMENDED if the newer
        # scripts for Rosetta 3.13 can be used instead, and is provided ONLY for scientific
        # reproducibility!
    
    # Scorefunctions are defined in this section.  These are primarily energy functions,
    # though they can be modified or enhanced with additional scoring terms for particular
    # tasks.
    <SCOREFXNS>
        <bnv weights="beta_nov15.wts" />
        <bnv_cst weights="beta_nov15_cst.wts" />
        <bnv_highhbond_cst weights="beta_nov15_cst.wts" >
            <Reweight scoretype=hbond_sr_bb weight=10.0 />
            <Reweight scoretype=hbond_lr_bb weight=10.0 />
            <Reweight scoretype=hbond_bb_sc weight=5.0 />
            <Reweight scoretype=hbond_sc weight=3.0 />
            <Reweight scoretype=fa_elec weight=2.0 />
        </bnv_highhbond_cst>
    </SCOREFXNS>
 
    # Movers are declared in this section.  These modify a structure in some way.
    <MOVERS>
        # The PeptideStubMover appends or prepends residues to an existing structure.
        <PeptideStubMover name=extend >
            <Prepend anchor_rsd=234 resname="GLY" />
            <Prepend anchor_rsd=234 resname="GLY" />
            <Prepend anchor_rsd=234 resname="GLY" />
            <Append anchor_rsd=238 resname="GLY" />
            <Append anchor_rsd=239 resname="GLY" />
            <Append anchor_rsd=240 resname="GLY" />
        </PeptideStubMover>
 
        # The AtomTree mover is used to define the kinematic relationships in the structure,
        # and to indicate which sections will move and which will remain fixed when a bond is
        # rotated.
        <AtomTree name=foldtree1 fold_tree_file="inputs/foldtree1.txt" />
 
        # The SetTorsion mover sets mainchain torsions to user-defined values.
        <SetTorsion name=initialize_tors>
            <Torsion residue=234 torsion_name=omega angle=180.0 />
            <Torsion residue=235 torsion_name=omega angle=180.0 />
            <Torsion residue=236 torsion_name=omega angle=180.0 />
            <Torsion residue=237 torsion_name=phi   angle=-60.0 />
            <Torsion residue=238 torsion_name=psi   angle=-10.0 />
            <Torsion residue=238 torsion_name=omega angle=180.0 />
            <Torsion residue=239 torsion_name=omega angle=180.0 />
            <Torsion residue=240 torsion_name=omega angle=180.0 />
        </SetTorsion>
 
        # The DeclareBond mover is used to connect the first and last residues of the
        # newly-extended peptide with an amide bond.  Currently, this bond geometry will be
        # badly distorted.
        <DeclareBond name=connect_termini atom1=N res1=234 atom2=C res2=241
            add_termini=true
        />
    </MOVERS>
 
    # Previously-defined movers are listed here as a series of steps to perform to define a
    # protocol.
    <PROTOCOLS>
        <Add mover=extend />
        <Add mover=foldtree1 />
        <Add mover=initialize_tors />
        <Add mover=connect_termini />
    </PROTOCOLS>
 
    # This section indicates the energy function that will be used to return a final score on
    # output.
    <OUTPUT scorefxn=bnv />
</ROSETTASCRIPTS>
